JACOB BARRETT DEMING

609-203-9531 · JacobDeming91@gmail.com

Extremely motivated Media Studies and Coding Bootcamp graduate with extensive knowledge of programming, web design, and game design principles seeking a full-time position within Game Development. Proficient in JavaScript, HTML, CSS, MySQL, Java, Unity, and Adobe Flash Professional, as shown through my over six years of working alongside and within the tech and gaming industries.

EDUCATION

Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey	New Brunswick, NJ
Major: Journalism and Media Studies	B.A. May 2014
Minor: Cinema Studies	
Cumulative GPA: 3.82, Magna Cum Laude and Dean's List	
Member, Kappa Tau Alpha National Honor Society in Journalism and Mass Communications	May 2014
Recipient of the distinguished Journalism and Media Studies Endowed Fund	July 2013
Recipient of Academic Excellence Award	April 2012

RELEVANT SKILLS

- **Game Design:** Adept in the process of designing gameplay elements, implementing them into a system, and balancing the product through the processes of user feedback and testing. Deep understanding of gaming theory, law, narrative, and production. Proficient in JavaScript, Node, Unity, Adobe Flash Professional, Adobe Illustrator, Java, HTML, and CSS.
- Research: Strong research skills ranging from quantitative to qualitative analysis of data. Experienced fact checker, ethnographer, and market analyst. Proficient in Microsoft Word, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft PowerPoint, and Prezi.
- Writing: Robust writing and editing skills extending to all forms of publication including journalism, reviews, screenplays, scholarly articles, blog posts, and online narratives followed by over 400 unique users.
- Video Production: Experienced in all aspects of developing multimedia content from conception through post-production. Proficient in video, photo, and audio recording with wide variety of equipment. Skilled with Final Cut Pro, Sony Vegas Pro, Adobe Premiere Pro, Fraps, Sony Sound Forge, Adobe Audition, Audacity, and film projection systems.

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Trilogy Education Services

New York, NY

Programming Consultant

April 2016 - Present

- Creates detailed JavaScript, Node, MySQL, and HTML lesson plans for use in a boot-camp setting
- Produces coding activities and comments solutions for those assignments created
- Reviews, updates, and modernizes old and outdated lesson plans and code to higher standards

Starboard Games LLC

PR Lead

Midlothian, VA

August 2015 – April 2016

• Directed PR campaigns for an independent game studio by providing weekly agendas, goals, and assignments

- · Managed newsletters, blogs, and provided outreach to additional communities to extend the company's reach
- Handled social media and provided regular updates on the narrative and technical aspects of the product

Big Tent EntertainmentNew York, NYGame Marketing InternSummer 2013

- Helped to test, market, and successfully launch a mobile game on the Apple App Store
- Conducted market analysis on gaming and mobile applications industry
- Created design documents and presentations for possible future projects

LEADERSHIP

Rutgers Game Swap "Level Up!"

New Brunswick, NJ

Co-Founder

Spring 2012, 2013, 2014 & 2015

- Worked with Rutgers Student Life to organize and run the popular annual gaming swap-meet at Geek Week
- Designed posters and flyers for the events whilst publicizing them through social media
- Managed and traded an average of 200 to 300 titles per event

Plangere Writing Center, Rutgers University

New Brunswick, NJ September 2011 – May 2014

Tutor and Session Chief

- Selected as an intern for Fall 2011, promoted to Session Chief, Spring 2013
- Tutored Students in Basic Composition, Expository Writing, and Research in Disciplines